unitedhealthcareonline.com 2006-11-15

# Transaction JSP Template

Privacy Policy

When you send UnitedHealthcare information about your patient, we will respect the privacy and the confidentiality of that information, as well as all other information that we accumulate. To safeguard our enrollees' privacy, we have adopted the following privacy principles and information practices: 

  1. **We respect our enrollees' privacy.** Every individual has an expectation of privacy in the administration of his/her personal information that includes sensitive benefit and claims information.
  2. **Our enrollees have the right to review and to correct their personal information.** They may review such information and notify us of errors or omissions.
  3. **We manage our enrollees' personal information with care.** We collect and maintain information to administer our business and to provide products, services and information of importance to our enrollees. We provide security safeguards in the handling and maintenance of our enrollees' information to protect against risks such as loss, destruction or misuse. We conduct regular audits to guarantee appropriate and secure handling and processing of our enrollees' information.
  4. **We do not engage in the sale or trading of mailing lists or personal information.**
  5. **We require our business affiliates to abide by our privacy principles.** In our business dealings, we hold our contractors, affiliated companies, and partners to the same high ethical standards in protecting your privacy by requiring that they pledge to uphold these privacy principles.
  6. **We will enforce our principles.** In holding our affiliates and ourselves to these privacy principles, we pledge to vigorously enforce sanctions for the violation thereof.

Our enrollees' benefit, claims and personal information are maintained in a secure environment. By using www.unitedhealthcareonline.com, you are able to access a wealth of information for your patients. Since these records may contain sensitive medical information, we ask you to take reasonable precautions when viewing our web sites. 

E-mail communications between patients, physicians and health organizations are increasing. You should be aware that there is a significant difference between the security of the transmission of data sent through www.unitedhealthcareonline.com and data which is not sent through www.unitedhealthcareonline.com. As detailed in our Security Statement, our site uses the highest levels of Internet security. We require the use of a secure browser and take full advantage of its features such as data encryption, Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol, user names, passwords and other tools. The system encrypts the login information and personal information that flows back and forth between you and us. 

If you choose to communicate with us using unsecured e-mail, please be aware that e-mail messages sent in clear text over the public Internet, as opposed to through www.unitedhealthcareonline.com, can be observed by an unintended third party. If you wish to keep your information or your patients' information private, please do not send sensitive or personal information or requests for sensitive or personal information unless you use a secure function within www.unitedhealthcareonline.com to do so. If you have inquiries regarding personal information, you may contact our Network Management relations liaison. 

We do maintain information about you and your activities while at our website. We use the information to troubleshoot problems and enforce our online agreements governing use of our site. At times, we may need to look across multiple users to identify or resolve problems or to resolve disputes. 

Our policy is to ask explicitly whenever we need information that personally identifies you. 

The registration form on our site requires you to give us unique identifiers (such as a User ID and password). We request your unique identifiers to verify your identity and for use in allowing you to access information in our computer system. 

Our site may require you to give us contact information (such as your name, daytime phone number and e-mail address). We use your contact information so you may take advantage of certain functionalities on our site, and to provide you information on our products and services.

We log your online transactions into our databases and keep a record of things you do such as changing your information, or requesting something from us. 

Our site may use an order form for users to request information, products, and services. We may also need to collect financial information or credit card numbers. We would use such financial information to bill you for the products and services you order, if any. 

We use your computer IP address and domain information to help diagnose problems with our server(s), and to administer our Web site. Your IP address and domain information is used to help identify you and to gather broad demographic information. For the same reason, we also capture information regarding which browser and operating system you may elect to use. 

In the future, we may request other personal information to provide you with the most advanced personalized web experience possible. 

If we provide advertiser-sponsored information, we would also use this information to allow our advertisers to reach the right audience. In this role, we would play the middleman. Advertisers would give us the advertisements and tell us the audience they would like to reach. We would then take the ad and display it to those of you meeting that criterion. Our approach benefits your privacy- the advertiser never has access to information about you individually. 

We may capture click streams to help us learn what parts of our site are most popular and among which audiences. We may also use them to help us optimize our user interface, to analyze site usage statistically, to improve content and to customize our site's content and layout. In short, we use this information to allow us to tailor our site and to meet your needs better. 

We analyze click stream data to track trends and behaviors. We use it in a way that's similar to a traffic report: it tracks trends and behaviors without identifying individuals. We are interested in our audience size, return visit rates, and similar data on an aggregate basis. 

As part of the click stream, we capture the URL you came from when you arrive at our site, as well which URL you go to next (whether or not this URL is on our site). We also capture date and time information of visits, pages visited, and the time you spend with us. 

Our online systems store your user information and online transaction history safely and securely. They also act as the place for us to generate aggregate site information. 

Cookies are pieces of information that a site transfers to your computer's hard drive for record-keeping purposes. They can make the site more useful by storing information about your preferences at our site. It is almost standard for any interactive web site to use cookies. Cookies do not identify a user, but they do identify a user's computer. Most browsers are set up to accept cookies. If you prefer, you can set your browser to refuse cookies. If you do, you may not be able to take full advantage of what a site has to offer. 

We do not use cookies to track, report on activity when you are not on our site, or pass your data to other sites. We do not use cookies to collect personal information such as your email address. We do not combine information collected through cookies with other personal information. We make no attempt to look at or examine other cookies or information that may be stored on your computer. 

We will not disclose any of our enrollees' or your personal information collected on the site. Our exceptions to this non-disclosure are when we: 

  * Believe in good faith that the law requires it; 
  * Need to protect our rights and property; 
  * Enforce our online agreements governing our sites; or 
  * Act to protect the interest of our enrollees, registered users, guests or others. 

If we receive a subpoena or similar legal process demanding release of any information about you, we will notify you before complying with the request, unless we believe law prohibits such notification or time does not permit it. We do not uniformly share information with outside parties, including government agencies. 

A third party, acting on our behalf, may write or call in the process of performing usability research about our site. Any research projects will clearly identify themselves. Our site researchers will never have access to your private health information and will never ask about your private health. 

This site contains links to other sites. We are not responsible for the privacy practices or the content of such other sites. We do attempt to influence connected sites to adopt similar policies. For more information on privacy issues, you may wish to contact: 

  * American Civil Liberties Union (ACLU) for pamphlets on consumer privacy 
  * Electronic Frontier Foundation 
  * Electronic Privacy Information Center (EPIC) for Privacy Information 
  * Health Privacy Project (HPP)
  * Privacy Issues Page from the Center for Democracy and Technology (CDT) 
  * The EPIC Cookies Page for news, definitions and links 
  * How to Protect Your Privacy from the Federal Trade Commission (FTC)
